D. BRYAN CHICK

Highlands Ranch, CO 80129

Phone: | Email: bryan_chick@outlook.com

LinkedIn: linkedIn: linkedin.com/in/bryan-chick/ | Github: github.com/bryanchick

SUMMARY

Python Developer who specialized as a Data Analyst with excellent technical skills and a background in education, training, and development. Hard working and a fast learner who is detail oriented as well as a great communicator who excels at both working as part of a team and in leadership roles facilitating guidance for successful project completion.

PROJECTS

Senator Tweets | GitHub link <u>github.com/bryanchick/project3</u> | weblink bryanchick.github.io/static/senatorTweet

- Over 290,000 tweets from US senators were grabbed from Twitter to find the rate of
 positive, negative and neutral tweets (using machine learning). The machine learning
 program also predicted which political party the senator belonged to based on the tweet.
- Co-Coded python for Twitter API and ML, visualization using Tableau
- Python, Tableau, Jupyter Notebook, BernoulliNB, LinerarSVC

Terrorism Trends | Github link <u>github.com/bryanchick/terrorismTrends</u> | weblink <u>bryanchick.github.io/static/terrorT</u>

- Data on the rise of national political parties in Europe was cross-referenced with data on the occurrence of terrorism in Europe to see if there was a correlation between the two.
- Co-Coded the python, and research terrorism counts for the country by using
 international terrorism guidelines. Used NYTimes and Guardian API to search count of
 terrorism activities/trends in Europe by keyword. Analyzed vote outcomes by country to
 determine the percent increase of the populist party.
- Python, NYTimes API, Jupyter Notebook, PowerPoint

Beatport Webscraping | GitHub link github.com/bryanchick/Project2 |

- The EDM top 100 chart was web-scraped from beatport.com and the data was visualized using line graphs.
- Wrote the HTML, CSS, Co-Coded python, Flask, and Javascript
- Python with BeautifulSoup, HTML, CSS, Flask, Plotly.js, Jupyter Notebook, Visual Studio Code, PowerPoint

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Data Analytics/Science: Python 3, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, BeautifulSoup, Plotly, JavaScript, D3.js, Geomapping with Leaflet.js, Plotly.js, Flask, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, MySQL, Talend, Tableau, Snowflake, MongoDB, Modeling & Forecasting, Dashboarding, Social Media Mining, Excel, Pivot Tables, Excel functions, VBA, Macro, API Interactions, ETL, AI, ML, BernoulliNB, LinerarSVC.

Operating Systems: Windows, macOS, Linux,

Other Software and Skills: Jupyter Notebook, Java beginner, Vim beginner, Google Docs, Office365 Exchange, Git Bash, Visual Studio Code, CRM Platforms, Performance Management, Regulation Research, Adobe Lightroom, Team Management, Schoology, Public Speaking, Project Management, Google Colab,

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate, Data Analytics: University of Denver, Denver, CO A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, pivot tables, Excel functions, Python, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

Teaching Certificate, Secondary Social Studies: Metropolitan State University, Denver, CO. Member of the Urban Teacher Program.

Bachelor of Arts, Classics: University of Colorado, Boulder, CO. The study of ancient history and archaeology of Rome and Ancient Greece. Latin, Ancient Greek.

EXPERIENCE

Social Studies Teacher, Cherry Creek Schools Greenwood Village CO 2013 - 2019

 Taught 6th and 7th grade Social Studies. Daily tasks included: data entry, inventory, lesson planning, public speaking, data analysis, data visualization, data forecasting, project management, critical thinking, communication with parents, supervisors, and coworkers. Held leadership positions and maintained an excellent rating in evaluations.

Team Leader, Kelly Services for CTB McGraw/Hill, Aurora CO 2012 - 2012

 Managed and monitored a team of contractors ensuring correct grading of California's standardized test.

Substitute Teacher, Cherry Creek Schools Greenwood Village CO 2009 - 2013

Worked in a variety of settings teaching a variety of different classes using materials
prepared by another teacher. Also held multiple long-term positions where all curriculum,
grading, and teacher duties were completed without assistance.